<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mattrbianchi</title>
    <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on mattrbianchi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 08:01:30 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>a peek into profiling go code</title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/a-peek-into-profiling-go-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 08:01:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/a-peek-into-profiling-go-code/</guid>
      <description>Some programmers consider profiling code to be some unknown magic that only wizards from A Great Age can do and only because of the years they&amp;rsquo;ve put in to the practice. I know because I used to be one of them. That is until I learned more about two handy tools under the extremely useful go command.
They make it easy for anyone to have a look under the hood of their Go code and are highly encouraged to by the community, but only when performance becomes a true concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reading</title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 22:14:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/reading/</guid>
      <description>I love getting professional opinions on books. Especially with technical books because they are time consuming to read and I want to get the most benefit from my time. That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m making this list to contribute my reviews so that other people can use them to make decisions on what to read to progress their own careers.
Table of Contents Books for All Developers
Learning About the Community</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>setup</title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 22:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/setup/</guid>
      <description>One thing I always try to search for after finding a really useful personal blog is a listing of the tools that person uses. Because if they have really good advice, they might use really good tools. Might. So in case someone (literally probably one person) wants to know the tools I use, here they are.
Hardware Laptop
 Macbook Pro 13&amp;rdquo; Retina display  Desktop
 Custom Build (simple) running Fedora 25 with Gnome desktop CODE keyboard (blue switches) Evoluent Vertical Mouse 4 Right (wired)  Work</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>resources</title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 22:13:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/resources/</guid>
      <description>A page of resources that I&amp;rsquo;ve found useful and want to keep forever, but don&amp;rsquo;t want clogging my bookmarks.
Developer Advice
Best Programming Advice I Ever Got
Seven Pillars of Pretty Code
Tenants of the Unix Philosophy
What ORMs have taught me: just learn SQL
HARMFUL GOTOS, PREMATURE OPTIMIZATIONS, AND PROGRAMMING MYTHS ARE THE ROOT OF ALL EVIL
Don&amp;rsquo;t Call Yourself A Programmer, And Other Advice
The Ultimate Code Kata</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 22:13:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Programmer, husband, recent Acme user, and now blogger.
I enjoy the great outdoors and the awesome tech community that New England has to offer. I also can&amp;rsquo;t turn down a good cup of coffee and love discussions around programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>treat your brain like a codebase</title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/treat-your-brain-like-a-codebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 07:01:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/treat-your-brain-like-a-codebase/</guid>
      <description>This post stems from me finding this conference talk. It would be best for you to watch it first and then come back, but don&amp;rsquo;t worry &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s pretty funny and really enlightening.
Death By a Thousand Cuts Now, after watching that talk, I realized that ever since I started to learn how to program, I was dying the death of a thousand micro-leaks because there was so much I didn&amp;rsquo;t know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>get started with acme</title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/get-started-with-acme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 15:36:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/get-started-with-acme/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve blabbed about how cool I think Acme is, I hope this post will help guide anyone else who is interested in trying this unique editor.
Installing Acme Mac Use Homebrew to install the Plan 9 tools like so: brew install plan9port
Linux Honestly I found it really easy to build from source following these instructions.
I did need to install the recommended xorg-dev package which was also painless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>first impressions of acme</title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/first-impressions-of-acme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 15:33:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/first-impressions-of-acme/</guid>
      <description>I suppose that after learning Go and falling in love with the community around it, it was inevitable that I would find Acme, Rob Pike&amp;rsquo;s and Russ Cox&amp;rsquo;s editor of choice, and shamelessly install it like the crazy fan boy I am. And I&amp;rsquo;m sure glad I did!
Join Me for a Nice Brew My first pleasant discovery was how easy it was to install this gem. If you&amp;rsquo;re on a Mac, it&amp;rsquo;s as easy as brew install plan9port, which actually provides you with all the tools from Plan 9, or so I&amp;rsquo;ve heard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>go is my spirit language</title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/go-is-my-spirit-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 15:10:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/go-is-my-spirit-language/</guid>
      <description>When I reveal my love for Go to fellow programmers, I often get inquired as to how this language could make me so passionate and exuberant. My response is usually to take a deep breath in preparation for what, in my mind, can only be an excellent delivery of my thoughts on Go. But what comes next is silence as I realize I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to lead with, followed by blurting anything that comes to mind like a rambling maniac.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>