<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Matthew Bianchi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 22:13:31 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 22:13:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Biography Programmer, husband, recent Acme user, and now blogger.
I enjoy the great outdoors and the awesome tech community that New England has to offer. I also can&amp;rsquo;t turn down a good cup of coffee and love discussions around programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Posts</title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/home/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/home/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Peek Into Profiling Go</title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/a-peek-into-profiling-go-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 08:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/a-peek-into-profiling-go-code/</guid>
      <description>Some programmers consider profiling code to be some unknown magic only wizards from A Great Age can do and they only can because of the years they&amp;rsquo;ve put in to the practice. I know because I used to be one of them until I learned more about two handy tools under the extremely useful go command.
These tools make it easy for anyone to have a look under the hood of their Go code and are highly encouraged to by the community, but only when performance becomes a true concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treat Your Brain Like A Codebase</title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/treat-your-brain-like-a-codebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 07:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/treat-your-brain-like-a-codebase/</guid>
      <description>This post stems from me finding this conference talk. It would be best for you to watch it first and then come back, but don&amp;rsquo;t worry &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s pretty funny and really enlightening.
Death By a Thousand Cuts Now, after watching that talk, I realized that ever since I started to learn how to program, I was dying the death of a thousand micro-leaks because there was so much I didn&amp;rsquo;t know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Started With Acme</title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/get-started-with-acme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 15:36:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/get-started-with-acme/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve blabbed about how cool I think Acme is, I hope this post will help guide anyone else who is interested in trying this unique editor.
Installing Acme Mac Use Homebrew to install the Plan 9 tools like so: brew install plan9port
Linux Honestly I found it really easy to build from source following these instructions.
I did need to install the recommended xorg-dev package which was also painless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Impressions Of Acme</title>
      <link>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/first-impressions-of-acme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 15:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mattrbianchi.com/post/first-impressions-of-acme/</guid>
      <description>I suppose that after learning Go and falling in love with the community around it, it was inevitable that I would find Acme, Rob Pike&amp;rsquo;s and Russ Cox&amp;rsquo;s editor of choice, and shamelessly install it like the crazy fan boy I am. And I&amp;rsquo;m sure glad I did!
Join Me for a Nice Brew My first pleasant discovery was how easy it was to install this gem. If you&amp;rsquo;re on a Mac, it&amp;rsquo;s as easy as brew install plan9port, which actually provides you with all the tools from Plan 9, or so I&amp;rsquo;ve heard.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>